# JOEL V. HARTUNG

### SUMMARY

**Dedicated library administrator** with a proven record of progressively responsible experience in systems administration, technical services, and project management. Have led key initiatives to improve the usability and access of resources, including a complete website redesign, the transition from a catalog to a discovery search interface, and the planning of a facilities renovation. Willing to relocate.

### EXPERIENCE

### **Assistant Director, Library Systems**

Apr. 2017 - Present

Freeman-Lozier Library, Bellevue University, Neb.

- Library administrative duties, including strategic planning and vendor management
- Managed library systems and digital archives repository

### **Systems Librarian**

June 2013 - Apr. 2017

Freeman-Lozier Library, Bellevue University, Neb.

- Administrator for library systems, including website, SirsiDynix ILS, and online resources
- Managed library technical support staff
- Coordinated the implementation of new library systems

# **SEO/Digital Marketing Specialist**

Oct. 2012 - June 2013

Gregg Young Chevrolet, Omaha, Neb.

- Managed vendors, website, CRM database, social media platforms, and online reputation
- Wrote, filmed, and edited marketing videos for YouTube and the dealership website

### **Student Navigator**

Jan. 2012 - May 2012

Education Library, McGill University, Montreal, QC, Canada

- Provided circulation, reference, and technical assistance to McGill University students
- Created and maintained library subject guides

# Search Engine Optimization/Taxonomy Intern

May 2011 - Aug. 2011

CBS Interactive, San Francisco, Cal.

- Developed navigational taxonomies for CBSi web properties
- Performed SEO activities, including keyword research and classification

#### **Technical Services Assistant**

Aug. 2009 - Aug. 2010

Calvin T. Ryan Library, University of Nebraska - Kearney, Neb.

### Library Aide

May 2004 - May 2008

Sump Memorial Library, Papillion, NE

### SKILLS

- Integrated Library System Administration (SirsiDynix Symphony)
- HTML & CSS
- AACR2 & Dublin Core Metadata Schema
- Adobe Creative Suite
- EZProxy

- Database Administration
- Video and Audio Editing
- Search Engine Optimization & Marketing
- Content Management System Administration (Wordpress, LibGuides)
- CONTENTdm

### **EDUCATION**

## **Master of Library and Information Studies**

May 2012

McGill University - Montreal, QC, Canada

### **Bachelor of Science: Communication**

May 2008

University of Nebraska - Omaha